DAYS!
By the decision of Ying Zheng, the king that wished to unite all of China,
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
天下統一の道を行く王 嬴政(えいせい)のもと
秦国(しんこく)は 隣国 魏(ぎ)への侵攻を開始した
the State of Qin began its invasion of the neighboring State of Wei.
Wang Ben, Meng Tian, and Xin.
王賁(おうほん) 蒙恬(もうてん) そして信(しん)
Three soldiers wishing to become Great Generals are gathered here
未来の大将軍たらんとする兵(つわもの)が―
今ここに集い
新しき時代を迎えようとしていた
trying to usher in a new age.
So you're Xin?
（郭備(かくび)）君が信か
フッ… 思ってたとおりの風貌だ
You look just as I expected.
I heard you used to be a servant.
君は 下僕の出らしいな
（信）ンッ…
I, Guo Bei, was originally a servant as well.
この郭備も 下僕の出身だ
Like you, I lost my parents to a war.
（郭備）何か力になってやろうと
勝手に思っていたが
フフッ… 要らぬ世話だったようだ
（信）えっ？
This unit is no fluke. Keep moving forward.
この隊は間違ってない
このまま進め
Let's not lose to any nobles or warrior class families, Xin!
貴士族なんかに負けるなよ 信
Thousand-Man General Guo Bei, please wait.
（輪虎(りんこ)）郭備千人将 お待ちを
（郭備）うん？
（兵士たちの泣き声）
（兵士たち）郭備さま！ 千人将！
Lord Guo Bei!
Thousand-Man General!
Thousand-Man General Guo Bei!
郭備千人将！
（兵士）千人将…
Thousand-Man General!
（尾平(びへい)たち）アッ… アア…
How the hell could this happen?!
こんなの ありかよ…
We were just talking with him!
ついさっきまで
俺たちと しゃべってたのに…
Thousand-Man General Guo Bei!
郭備千人将…
Just watch, I swear I'll avenge you!
見てろよ
敵(かたき)は絶対 取ってやるからな！
Some remnants of the State of Wei guys were hiding around here!
（去亥(きょがい)）魏国のヤツらの残党が
どっかに隠れてやがったんだ！
They might still be around here!
（田永(でんえい)）
まだ その辺にいるかもしれねえ
俺たちも捜そうぜ 信！
Let's look, too, Xin!
Of course!
当ったり前だ！ ５人１組で散れ！
Break into groups of five!
We'll search every nook and cranny of this place until we catch the guy that killed Thousand-Man General Guo Bei!
草の根分けてでも―
郭備千人将を斬ったヤツを
捕まえっぞ！
Big trouble!
（騎兵Ａ）大変だー！
What? Did they already find the enemy?
何だ？ もう敵が見つかったのか？
It wasn't just Lord Guo Bei!
（騎兵Ｂ）郭備さまだけではない！
Thousand-Man General Bi Zhi...
比至(ひし)千人将も！
and Thousand-Man General Ma Gao were slain as well!
（騎兵Ａ）
馬告(ばこく)千人将も討たれている
な… なんだと！
What?!
（崇原(すうげん)）千人将が…
（竜有(りゅうゆう)）３人も…
Three...
Thousand-Man Generals?
What the hell...
一体 何が…
is going on?
何が起こってるんだ…
（陸(りく)）アッ… アア…
Let's see... huh?
（輪虎）え～っと…
あれ？ さっき斬ったのが馬告か
The last one I killed was Ma Gao?
Then who's this?
じゃ これ誰だっけ？
（副官）輪虎さま
Lord Lun Hu, we must be going soon.
（副官）そろそろ脱出しませんと…
さすがに 秦国のヤツらも
騒がしくなってきました
As expected, the State of Qin men are getting boisterous.
Right, right. I think I'll get this guy next.
はいはい
次は この人にしよ～っと
Okay then.
それでは…
I'll slay another one or two and call it a night.
あと１人か２人斬って
今夜は おいとましますか
Air of a Military Commander
（部下）おい 聞いたか？
（部下）どこの者だ？
Even Thousand-Man General Lu was killed!
（部下Ａ）
陸千人将までも討たれたぞ
（部下Ｂ）これは たかが
残党風情の仕業と侮ってはおられぬ
This is beyond what we can blame on the likes of enemy remnants!
（部下Ｃ）手だれの刺客が
いるものと見ねばなるまい
This can only be the work of a skilled assassin.
Being in such unfamiliar territory,
（部下Ｄ）
不慣れな場所であるうえに
夜となれば やっかいな状況だぞ！
we could be in real danger come nightfall!
Do not panic!
（羅元(らげん)）うろたえるな！
巡回の警備隊を３倍に増やせ
Triple the security units on patrol!
Yes sir!
（部下たち）はっ！
（羅元）城門を固く閉ざし
Keep all castle gates strictly closed! Do not let a single person through!
１人も通すな！
（部下たち）はっ！
Yes, sir!
うん？
（蒙恬）羅元将軍
General Luo Yuan!
（羅元）おお 若！
Oh, Young Master!
I've been hearing about a rat sneaking in.
（蒙恬）ネズミが紛れ込んだとか
ああ… なかなか
大きな牙を持ったネズミじゃ
Yes. A rat with considerably large fangs.
既に 千人将を６人失った
We've already lost six Thousand-Man Generals.
６人も…
Six?
How is the Supreme Commander's guard?
（蒙恬）総大将の守りは？
（羅元）問題ない　白老さまは
もともと用心深いうえに―
No cause for concern.
In addition to the White Elder's usual wariness, we have tightened his level of security.
更に 守備兵も増やしておられる
But regardless, you should be careful as well, Young Master.
それより 若も気をつけられよ
The Yuehua Unit may be a 300-Man Unit, but your rating is already that of a Thousand-Man General, Young Master.
楽華(がくか)隊は三百人隊だが
若の格付けは 既に千人将だ
刺客に狙われておるやもしれぬぞ
You may be targeted by assassins.
その刺客についてですが
何か違和感を覚えませんか？
About those assassins, does this
affair feel strange at all to you?
うん？
（蒙恬）聞いたところ―
From what I've heard, the slain Thousand-Man Generals
討たれた千人将は いずれも
本軍の主力を担う武将ばかり
were all military commanders that form a central part of the Main Army's strength.
They're clearly seeking out people of major importance.
明らかに
実力者を選んで狙い撃ちをしている
It's as though someone hired by a State of Wei general
まるで 魏国の将軍を務める誰かが
この先の大戦のために
布石を打っているかのようです
is performing a strategic move in anticipation of the upcoming major battle.
フッ…
蒙家は 若の代で ますます安泰だな
The Meng family will be much safer with your generation.
だが
若のお考えは 少し深きに過ぎよう
However, I feel you may have read too deeply into things, Young Master.
With the death of Wu Qing, there is no general of the State of Wei that would attempt a strategic move of that caliber.
呉慶(ごけい)亡きあと
今から布石を打ってくるほどの―
戦略を持つ将軍など
魏国には いない
This assassination affair is an attempt at a counterattack by remnants of the Wei Army that
今 起こっている暗殺騒ぎは
この近利関(きんりかん)の城内に潜んでいる―
魏国の軍の残党が刺客となって
せめてもの反撃をしているのだ
are still hiding here at the Jinli Barrier castle.
千人将が狙われているのは―
The fact that Thousand-Man Generals are being targeted
それより上位の武将の警備が
厳しいからだろう
is likely due to the heavy security of higher ranked military commanders.
警備の薄い千人将が
狙われているのは―
I think you're correct in thinking that Thousand-Man Generals are being targeted because of their thin security,
間違いないでしょう
but please, be careful, General Luo Yuan!
しかし どうか
お気をつけください 羅元将軍
It is of course a major blow to lose skilled Thousand-Man Generals,
有能な千人将を失うのは
もちろん痛手ですが
それ以上に
将軍の代わりは利きません
but a full general cannot be replaced.
If even you are killed,
もし あなたが討たれでもしたら
the capability of this army led personally by General Meng Ao will be remarkably diminished.
蒙驁(もうごう)将軍が自ら率いる この軍の
機能は 著しく低下する
うむ… 分かっている
Yes, I know.
But do not fear!
だが 案ずるな！
刺客は今夜中に捕らえて斬首に処す
The assassins will be captured tonight and beheaded!
But the State of Qin Army was not able to capture the assassins.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）しかし 結局 秦国軍は
刺客を捕らえることができなかった
On that night, the Meng Ao Army lost eight Thousand-Man Generals.
この夜 蒙驁軍は一夜にして
８人もの千人将を失ったのである
And then, three days later...
そして ３日後
次の城に向かって
進軍を始めた蒙驁軍の様子は―
Setting out on their march to the next castle, the Meng Ao Army
厳重そのものであった
is the picture of stringency.
Look, Lord Ben.
（番陽(ばんよう)）ご覧ください 賁さま
The headquarters around General Meng Ao
（番陽）
蒙驁将軍のおられる本営の周りを
重武装の兵たちが
ぎっしり囲んでおりますぞ
is packed full with heavily armed soldiers.
It sounds like Young Master's advice was a bit too effective.
（じい）
若の忠告が 効き過ぎましたかな
Now it's not only assassins, but even allies cannot get close to the White Elder.
これでは 刺客どころか味方でも
白老さまには近づけませぬわ
This level of solid defense is the same as you'd have in the middle of an intense battle.
ここまで防御を固めるとは
激しい合戦の最中と同じだ
Is Grandfather sensing something?
じいさまも何か感じ取っているのか
羅元将軍の周りにも 隙は全くない
There aren't even any gaps around general General Luo Yuan.
There's no way an assassin could make an attack here.
これを
刺客が襲うことなど ありえない
それは あまりにも非現実的だ
That's just unrealistic.
What's that?
何だ？
For a moment there...
今 一瞬…
What's wrong, Xin?
（尾平）どうした？ 信
I thought I felt a chill...
寒気を感じたような…
Hey, Xin.
（尾平）おい 信
（信）ハッ…
What's up?
（尾平）どうした？
Ah, nothing. Let's go.
（信）いや… 何でもねえ　行こう
What exactly is going on, General Lian Po?
（景湣王(けいびんおう)）
どういうことか？ 廉頗(れんぱ)将軍
そのほうの側近が
僅か300人を率いて―
I heard that you sent your aide leading a mere 300 men
秦国軍の武将を
討ちに向かったと聞いたぞ
to attack State of Qin Army military commanders.
I would have given him thousands of soldiers.
（景湣王）わしに言えば
数千の兵を与えたものを
Lun Hu will not misjudge his own ability.
（廉頗）輪虎は 決して
己の力量を見誤ったりはせぬ
あやつが300と言うなら
300で間違いない
If he says to give him 300, then 300 is without a doubt what he needs.
し… しかし 300では
野営の端を襲うのが精いっぱい
But the most 300 men can do is attack the edge of an encampment.
とても 万を超す大軍の武将などを
討つことなどできまい
It would be utterly impossible to attack military commanders of a huge force of over 10,000.
And isn't Lun Hu that girlish-looking young boy?
しかも 輪虎とは確か
あの女子(おなご)のごとき少年であろう
ほう…
Are you suggesting that the spear that I, Lian Po, threw was weak?!
この廉頗の放った“槍(やり)”が
軽いと仰せか？
アッ… そ… そうは言わぬが
Th-That is not what I mean...
Very well!
よろしい　見た目でしか
人を量れぬ大王のために―
Since you cannot judge people on anything but how they look, your majesty,
分かりやすく お教えいたそう
I will explain it so it is easy for you to understand!
Do you know of the State of Qin's Six Great Generals?
秦国の六大将軍をご存じか？
（景湣王）なっ…
も… もちろん知って…
（廉頗）いや！
Of course I know of th—
No.
You do not!
ご存じない
（景湣王）なに？
What?
フッ…
（景湣王）な… 何じゃ？ 廉頗
Wh-What is it, Lian Po?
廉頗…
Lian Po?!
It was a feeling like hot lead had been driven into my guts...
（廉頗）それは 正に 土手っ腹に
焼けた鉛をたたき込まれた心地
The times when I confronted an army led by one of those Six Great Generals.
あの六大将軍が率いる軍勢と
対峙(たいじ)するとき
No matter how many times we fought,
幾度となく戦っていても―
毎回 内臓が押しつぶされるほどの
重圧を浴びせられまする
I was met with a pressure like my internal organs were being crushed.
Especially when I met with that Wang Qi's army.
特に あの王騎(おうき)の軍と来たら
幾重にも張り巡らされたヤツの
防御陣は 正に鉄壁
His many layers of defensive
formations were truly an iron wall!
ヤツの首を取ろうとすることは―
Trying to take that man's head
この身を裸にして
鋼鉄の壁に ぶつかるようなものだ
was like throwing one's own naked body against a steel wall.
But!
しかし！
Lun Hu did that!
輪虎は それをやる
And what's more, he eventually opened a crack in that steel wall.
（廉頗）更に あやつは
その鋼鉄の壁に 風穴を開け―
And through it, he crossed swords...
その先の王騎に…
with Wang Qi.
刃(やいば)をたたき込んだ
So perhaps now you understand.
分かったようじゃのぅ
If Lun Hu says 300, then 300 is plenty.
輪虎が300と言えば 300で十分
Once he is released from my hands,
ひと度
わしの手から放たれた あやつは
もはや 誰にも止められぬわ
no one can stop him!
（兵士）ウ… ウワーッ！
（兵士）た… 大変だ！
Xin
B-Big trouble!
将軍！ 羅元将軍！
The general! General Luo Yuan!
General Luo Yuan!
羅元将軍！
General Luo Yuan was...
羅元将軍が…
（兵士）羅元将軍が討たれたぞー！
General Luo Yuan was slain!
What?!
なに！
No way! How in the world...?!
（蒙恬）
バカな… 一体 どうやって？
The assassin is leading an ambush!
（兵士）刺客は伏兵を率いている！
その数300！
（兵士）来たぞ！
There are 300 of them!
They're here!
The enemy is a 300-Man Unit!
敵は三百人隊だ！
Over there!
三百人隊？
（兵士）そっちに行ったぞ！
A 300-Man Unit?
（兵士）敵は斜面を下ったぞ！
（兵士）下の部隊 包囲しろ！
The enemy is going down the slope!
Units below, surround them!
Don't let them get away!
ヤツらを逃がすなー！
ンンッ… あいつらが
It's them!
It's the enemy 300-Man Unit that killed General Luo Yuan!
（渕(えん)）
羅元将軍を討った敵の三百人隊です
I'll bet you they're the ones that took out Thousand-Man General Guo Bei, too!
（松左(しょうさ)）郭備千人将を討ったのも
きっと あいつらだ！
All right!
Let's get revenge...
（信）郭備千人将の敵を…
for Thousand-Man General Guo Bei!
取ってやるぜ！
（兵士たち）お… おう！
（兵士たち）おう！
What do you think, Lord Lun Hu?
（副将）
いかがいたしましょう？ 輪虎さま
小物は放っておこう
蹴散らして素通りする
Let's leave the small fries.
Just push them out of the way and head through.
ンッ… 止められた？
He stopped it?!
アッ… ウワッ！
ウワッ！ アアッ！
（どよめき）
（兵士）隊長！
Captain!
隊長！
Y-You bastard, leggo—
て… てめえ 手を… いてっ！
Let go of my ha—
くそ！ 手をはな… ウワッ！
（枝に ぶつかる音）
ウワッ！ アアッ！
アアッ… いてっ…
ンンッ… 何だ？ こいつの握力は
Just how strong is this guy's grip?!
You bastard, let go of...
てめえ！
離しやが… あっ！
ウワーッ！ ンンッ…
Dammit!
くそ… ヤーッ！ ざけんなよ！
Don't fuck with me!
えっ？ ウッ… ウワーッ！
Lord Lun Hu.
輪虎さま
先に行け　僕も すぐに行く
Go on ahead. I'll come in a moment.
Lun Hu?
輪虎？
That's odd.
（輪虎）変だなぁ
この僕の殺気にも
ひるまなかったし 剣も かわされた
You didn't balk at my bloodlust.
And you even used your sword.
Perhaps I've gotten rusty...
僕の腕が落ちたのか…
それとも―
Or maybe you're really strong.
君が とっても強いのか
Which is it?
どっち？
（信）ンンッ…
Of course I'm strong!
俺が強(つえ)えに決まってんだろうが！
（輪虎）だよね　お名前は？
Ah, yes.
What's your name?
Xin of the Feixin Unit.
飛信(ひしん)隊の信だ
ハハハハッ… 素直
Aren't you honest?
Ah, Xin of the Feixin Unit isn't written here.
あれ？ 書いてないね
飛信隊の信って名前は
I guess I won't be forced to kill you, then.
だったら ムリに殺すこともないか
フフフフッ…
Looks like your life is spared.
命拾いしたね 君
Now, I must be going.
じゃ これで
あっ… ま… 待ちやがれ！
Wait one damn second!
てめえが郭備千人将を斬ったのか？
Did you kill Thousand-Man General Guo Bei?!
Ah, you're right. Yes, it seems I did kill him.
あっ ホントだ
確かに僕が斬ってるね… そっか
Oh right. The quick one, the moment he turned around.
あの振り向きざまにスパッといった
ざけんな！
Fuck you!
He stopped it again?!
また止められた…
ハハッ… こんなに重いのは久々だ
It's been quite a while since I've caught such a heavy strike.
It looks like despite his age, this boy has quite some experience.
どうやら この子は
この若さで 相当 場数を踏んでいる
It's shallow. You can dodge that, too?
浅い… これも かわすんだ？
Oh my. This is a real surprise.
おやおや… これは本当に驚いたな
It's just a little, but this boy already has the air of a military commander about him.
ほんの僅かだけど この子は
既に 武将の空気をまといつつある
He has far more than the Thousand-Man Generals I slew.
今回 僕が討った千人将たちより
よっぽど
この子のほうが“持ってる”な
So young sprouts like this are coming out of the State of Qin as well?
秦国にも
こんな若い芽が出てきているのか
フッ… 殿だったら
成長が楽しみだとか言いそうだけど
My lord would probably say something like "I'm anticipating your growth", but...
unfortunately I'm not interested in that sort of thing.
あいにく僕には そんな趣味はない
Sorry, but but I'll be rooting out any enemy that catches my eye.
悪いけど 目につく敵は
根こそぎ狩らせてもらうよ
ウラッ！
Captain!
（兵士たち）隊長ーっ！
Help Lord Xin!
信どのを助けろ！
（松左）今行くぞ！
We're coming!
Xin!
（尾平）信！
（信）お前ら…
Guys...
Captain!
Hold on!
待て！ てめえは 一体 何者(なにもん)だ？
Who the hell are you?!
You're acting like an assassin, but are you a 300-Man General, too?!
刺客まがいのことをやってるが
お前も三百人将なのか？
It's true that I'm leading a 300-Man Unit at the moment,
確かに 今回は
三百人隊を率いているけれども―
三百人将ではないよ
but I am not a 300-Man General.
Depending on the time and place, I may lead a thousand or ten thousand.
時と場合によっては
千も率いれば 万も率いる
I am a fully-fledged general.
僕は れっきとした将軍だよ
What?! A Full General?!
なに！ 将軍？
You liar!
…て ウソつけ！
お前みてえな ひねた子供が
将軍のわけねえだろうが！
There's no way in hell a twisted kid like you's a Full General!
“ひねた子供”って ひどいな…
僕は こう見えても30代なんだけど
Twisted kid? That's so mean.
Despite how I look, I'm in my thirties.
Th-Thirties?!
さ… 30代！
I suppose I really should quit for today.
やっぱり今日は やめておこうか
You seem to be adored by your comrades.
君は仲間に慕われているみたいだね
いいことだよ
That's good.
そういう人間は
えてして 天にも好かれている
Those sorts of people are often beloved by the heavens.
The heavens?
天？
No matter how much talent or ability one has,
（輪虎）
いくら才能や実力があっても―
“幸運”という天の働きがないと
武将なんて 道半ばで命を落とすよ
unless you have that heavenly thing called "luck",
you'll lose your life part way down your path as a military commander.
そういう武将を大勢 見てきた
I've seen tons of commanders like that.
Take those Thousand-Man Generals that just died.
例えば ほら
今回 討たれた千人将たちとか
てめえが やったんだろうが！
But that was you that did that!
There's truly... only a handful of military generals beloved by the heavens.
（輪虎）本当に―
天に愛される武将は
ほんの ひと握り
Uh... Huh?
…て
あら？ なんで こんな話を君に？
Why am I talking to you about this?
Oh, right.
ああ そっか
この子のキラキラした感じが
どこか―
I thought that the sort of twinkling feeling this boy has...
felt kind of similar to those people's.
あの人たちに似てると思ったからか
Xin of the Feixin Unit.
飛信隊の信
（信）あっ…
I'll write your name on my scroll later.
あとで
巻物に君の名前を書き込んでおくよ
あっ… 待て！
Wait!
I'll let you go this one time.
見逃すのは一度だけだ
次に どこかで出会ったなら―
But if we meet again somewhere,
your life is mine!
必ず命をもらう
Captain!
（兵士たち）隊長！
（尾平）信 大丈夫か？ 信！
Xin, are you okay?
Xin?
That guy ran, eh?
（沛浪(はいろう)）あいつ 逃げやがったか
どうする？ 信　追っかけるか？
What do we do, Xin?
Should we follow him?
Military commanders beloved by the heavens...
天に愛される武将…
Xin?
（昂(こう)）信？
What the hell's that mean?
（信）何だ？ そりゃ
Preview
Midnight Great General
End